DENNIS SAGAYANATHAN

Contact

Address:

D-401, Archana Greens, NIBM Road, Pune – 411048, Maharashtra.

Phone:

+91 73910 73277

Email:

dennis.sag@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/d3n

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Tamil
- Marathi
- French
- Japanese

Summary

A Master's student in Software Engineering with a passion to make a difference. Has remarkable extracurricular success. Extensive leadership experience in the higher education setting. Adaptable with departments, faculties, administrators, and peers. Good communication and speaking skills. Possesses fast learning abilities and is committed to succeeding.

Experience

Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Intern – Mar 2019 to Jun 2019 Paymint Global Payment Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Pune.

- Worked for 3 months on the organization's website.
- Optimized the website to appear in the Top 2 Pages of a Google Search, if relevant.
- Gained team skills as well as leadership skills with my fellow interns.
- Followed structured working as well as on-time work completion.

Co – Founder – Mar 2020 to Present GRCO Consulting

- Working on various software consulting assignments.
- Working on providing robust and secure AI solutions to our clients.
- Working on providing business intelligence and analysis to our clients.

Education

SIGMA Clermont, France.

One semester at SIGMA Clermont, Clermont-Ferrand,
France, with the French Government Scholarship.

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai.

 Master of Technology (Integrated Course): Software Engineering – 2019 to 2024

The Orbis School, Pune.

 Higher Secondary Education: Math, Science and Informatics Practices – 2017 to 2019

The Bishop's School, Pune.

Primary and Secondary Education: Math, Science, Computer Science and French – 2005 to 2017

Volunteering

Organizing Committee Member – Jun 2020 to Oct 2020

TEDxVITChennai

Was responsible for the Sponsorship and Finance, along with the Logistics of the event.

Honors and Awards

- Runner-Up of the Rolls-Royce's R² Data Labs Responsible Growth Hack
- French Government Scholarship Holder, issued by the Government of the French Republic as Campus France's Charpak Exchange Scholarship
- Winner in the Smart India Hackathon (University Level), 2020.
- Runner-Up in the National Level of Microsoft Office Specialist, 2018. (Excel 2013 Specialist)

Licenses and Certifications

- Microsoft Office Specialist Excel 2013 Microsoft
- The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Google
- Introduction to Packet Tracer Cisco
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) Bridging Cisco
- Python for Data Science IBM
- IBM Cloud Essentials IBM
- IBM Blockchain Foundation Developer IBM
- Deep Learning using TensorFlow IBM
- DataOps Methodology IBM
- Postman Student Expert Postman
- R Essentials IBM
- IBM Blockchain Essentials V2 IBM
- Docker Essentials: A Developer Introduction IBM
- Deep Learning Essentials IBM
- Deep Learning IBM
- Data Science Tools IBM
- Data Analysis Using Python IBM
- Cloud Core IBM
- Accelerated Deep Learning with GPU IBM
- Transformer Models and BERT Model Google
- Share Data Through the Art of Visualization Google
- Process Data from Dirty to Clean Google
- Prepare Data for Exploration Google
- Introduction to Large Language Models Google
- Introduction to Image Generation Google
- Introduction to Generative AI Google
- Google Data Analytics Specialization Google (Professional Certificate)
- Google Data Analytics Capstone: Complete a Case Study Google
- Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere Google
- Encoder-Decoder Architecture Google

- Data Visualization Using Python IBM
- Data Analysis with R Programming Google
- Create Image Captioning Models Google
- Attention Mechanism Google
- Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions Google
- Applied Data Science with Python Level 2 IBM
- Analyze Data to Answer Questions Google
- Algorithmic Toolbox UC San Diego
- Responsible AI: Applying AI Principles with Google Cloud
- Introduction to Responsible AI Google
- Generative AI Fundamentals Google

Skills

- C, C++, Java, MySQL
- Python
- Deep Learning
- Data Structures
- Data Warehousing
- Data Visualization

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/Django
- Search Engine Optimization
- OpenCV
- Machine Learning
- Data Analytics
- Data Mining

Hobbies

- Playing Instruments Piano, Guitar.
- Competitive Coding / Programming
- Public Speaking
- Debating
- Music Production